neverware.com 2019-12-26

# Privacy — Neverware

## Our Privacy Policy Summary

At Neverware, your privacy is critical to us. We prize transparency as one of our core company values; accordingly, we strive to be as transparent as possible about the personal information we collect and how we use it. Updates in this version of the Neverware Privacy Policy reflect recent changes in data protection laws, including the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

Our policies for privacy and data protection can be summarized as:

  * We only collect data in order to improve the customer experience for Neverware’s products and services.

  * We will never sell any of your personal data.

  * When your data is shared with third-party tools and services, it remains under Neverware’s control.

  * Our goal is to meet or exceed the legal requirements for personal protection in any jurisdiction, and to provide all users and customers the same rights.

## What This Policy Covers

This policy is intended to help you understand:

  * What information we collect about you

  * How we use the information we collect

  * How we share information we collect

  * How long we keep this data

  * How to access and control your information

This Privacy Policy covers the information we collect about you when you use our websites, products or services, or otherwise interact with us (for example, by registering for our online events or downloading our content), unless a different policy is displayed. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into, and considered a part of, the Neverware Terms of Service, currently located at <https://www.neverware.com/tos>.

Please also note that co-branded websites (websites where Neverware presents content together with one or more of our business partners) may be governed by additional or different privacy statements. Please refer to the privacy statement on those websites for more information about applicable privacy practices.

This policy also explains your choices regarding how we use information about you. Your choices include how you can object to certain uses of information about you and how you can access and update certain information about you. If you do not agree with this policy, do not access or use our products or services or interact with any other aspect of our business.  

## The Personal Information We Collect

 **1\. CloudReady Operating System**

CloudReady is provided to users and customers for use on their own devices as a full operating system. In this section, “CloudReady OS” refers to that OS once you have started using it on your device.

 _What data CloudReady OS collects and what we use it for:_

  *  **Hardware Info:** We collect data about the devices you run CloudReady OS on, including the names, manufacturers, and capabilities of each computer and its components. We use this info to provide a unique ID for licensing purposes (on CloudReady Education and Enterprise Editions), to estimate the volume of total CloudReady users at any time, and to better understand and improve CloudReady's compatibility with different hardware.

  *  **Startup and Login Metrics:** Neverware tracks the frequency with which CloudReady devices are powered on or logged in, and pairs that with info about the version of CloudReady a device is running. This info allows us to estimate the total number of CloudReady users over any given time span, and to infer the stability of CloudReady in conjunction with hardware data.

  *  **Feature Info:** Neverware also collects data about your use of some specific features like Flatpaks applications and Docker (currently only on the Home Edition of CloudReady).

 _Personal privacy and opting out on CloudReady OS:_

  *  **Personal Privacy:** Hardware and usage data are only tied to your device’s identity. No personally identifiable information is collected. For Home Edition users, hardware identity is pseudonymized using a cryptographic hash to ensure anonymity.

  *  **Opting Out:** All collected data is required by Neverware to be able to enforce licensing and provide support on CloudReady Education and Enterprise Editions. Users of the Home Edition can opt out of sending data at any time in their CloudReady settings menu.

 _How long we keep the data that CloudReady OS collects:_

  * CloudReady OS does not collect any personally identifiable information, and as such, Neverware retains the above device information indefinitely for the purpose of historical reporting.

 **2\. CloudReady feedback tool**

The CloudReady feedback tool sends robust system logs to Neverware, at a user’s discretion, in the case of disruptive OS errors such as kiosk app failures, licensing issues, sign-in errors, or any time a user manually selects “Report an issue” in the browser settings menu.

 _What data the CloudReady feedback tool collects and what we use it for:_

  *  **System Logs:** We collect a full suite of system logs from your CloudReady device when you send us information using the feedback tool. For an example of what data is contained in these logs, [visit this knowledge base article](https://cloudreadykb.neverware.com/s/article/What-info-is-collected-when-I-send-feedback-logs). We use this broad set of data to provide our support and engineering team as much context and information as possible when addressing the problem that initiated the CloudReady feedback tool’s use.

 _Personal privacy and opting out of the CloudReady feedback tool:_

  *  **Personal Privacy:** System logs redact all your personally identifiable information except your email address, should you choose to include it.

You can view the logs you have sent to Neverware by sending a request to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#89ede8fde8a4e0e7f8fce0fbe0ecfac9e7ecffecfbfee8fbeca7eae6e4). Education and Enterprise users can also visit my.Neverware.com to access their site’s logs.

  *  **Opting Out:** If you do not want to share system logs with CloudReady, you are not required to send us system logs. You can cancel or avoid any sending of logs by never pressing “alt+shift+i” when using CloudReady, never selecting “Report an issue…” from the CloudReady settings menu, and cancelling any prompt that asks you to send logs.

Note that some OS functionality is not possible if you choose not to send us logs. Licensing errors can only be resolved by sending Neverware logs or by [contacting our support team](https://www.neverware.com/support), so that the issue can be understood and resolved. If you experience a licensing error and choose not to send logs, you will not be able to proceed using CloudReady.

 _How long we keep the data that the CloudReady feedback tool collects:_

  * Neverware retains logs you send us for 30 days by default. If your logs are relevant to an ongoing investigation or improvement, we retain these logs for the duration of the work they are relevant to.

You can request to have your logs deleted by sending a request to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#97f3f6e3f6bafef9e6e2fee5fef2e4d7f9f2e1f2e5e0f6e5f2b9f4f8fa).

 **3\. Neverware.com Website and Sub Domains**

Defined as all of the neverware.com domain, the try.neverware.com and go.neverware.com sub domains, and the neverware.zendesk.com domain, (together the “site”), except for the my.Neverware.com sub domain as noted below.

 _What data the site collects and what we use it for:_

  * Neverware collects personal information directly from you when you interact with us through our site, including, without limitation, when you:

    * Sign up for a free trial of CloudReady OS

    * Make online purchases

    * Request support

    * Register for a webinar or other event

    * Request information or materials (e.g., case studies or brochures)

    * Sign up for our newsletter or similar email lists

    * Participate in surveys or evaluations

    * Participate in promotions, contests, or giveaways

    * Apply for employment

    * Submit questions or comments

    * Submit content or posts on our blog, user forums, knowledge base, or other interactive web pages

  * We may also collect information relating to your use of the site and response to our emails through the use of various technologies. Collecting information in this manner allows us to analyze the effectiveness of our websites and our marketing efforts, personalize your experience, and improve our interactions with you. For more information about the technologies we employ for these purposes, see the **Cookies and Tracking Policy** section below, which includes information on how to control or opt out of these cookies and tracking technologies.

  * Neverware uses personal information in an effort to enhance your experience on our site. In addition, we may use personal information we collect about you to:

    *  **Fulfill Your Requests.** If you request something from Neverware, such as a product or service, a call back, or specific marketing or other materials, we may use the personal information you provide to respond your request. We or our representatives may also contact you as part of customer satisfaction surveys or for market research purposes.

    *  **Provide You with Information About Our Products, Services and Events.** Neverware may use your personal information to notify you about product and service offerings as well as events that we believe may be of interest to you. We also may use your personal information to respond directly to your requests for information, including registrations for newsletters or other specific requests.

    *  **Provide Support and Customer Service.** We may use your personal information to provide support for products or services you have obtained from us and answer other questions.

    *  **Process Your Job Application.** When you apply for a position at Neverware, we use the personal information you provide, such as information in your resume and cover letter, for the purpose of assessing your application, considering you for future positions and carrying out human resources functions in accordance with applicable law.

We will not use your personal information in a manner that is inconsistent with the purpose of its original collection, unless you have consented.

 _Personal privacy and opting out on Neverware.com website and sub domains:_

  *  **Personal Privacy:** To the extent permitted by applicable law, the types of personal information collected directly from you may include, without limitation:

    * Information used to communicate with you, such as name, job title, company name, email address, telephone number, and postal address

    * Information contained in your job inquiries or applications, such as resume, cover letter, age, education, professional history and contact details

    * Information that Neverware maintains in association with your account, such as your username, password, payment information, purchase records, credit and billing status and support inquiries

  *  **Opting Out:** See the **Cookies and Tracking Policy** below, which includes information on how to control or opt out of these cookies and tracking technologies. Otherwise, please reference the **How to View, Correct, or Delete our Data About You** section for further information.

 _How long we keep the data that the Neverware.com domain collects:_

  * If we have no interaction with you for 36 months, we will delete any superfluous personally identifiable information stored about you. Users of our site, products, or services can request to have personally identifiable information and activities deleted by sending a request to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#41252035206c282f30342833282432012f24372433362033246f222e2c).

 **4\. The my.Neverware user/admin portal**

Defined as the entirety of sites you might visit whose URLs are in the my.neverware.com subdomain.

 _What data my.Neverware collects and what we use it for:_

  *  **Personal Data:** When you sign up for my.Neverware, we collect info on your name, email address, phone number, and the organization you work for. We use this data to understand your use case with CloudReady, and to contact you about purchasing or using CloudReady and my.Neverware.

  *  **Activity:** When you visit my.Neverware, we track your activity across different pages and the different actions you may initiate within the portal. We use this information to better understand what you have been working on in the event that a sales or support interaction should need additional context. We also provide this data back to you under the “Activity” tab.

 _Personal privacy and opting out on my.Neverware:_

  *  **Personal Privacy:** While you are a user of my.Neverware, the personal data you provide us, and activity data about your use of the portal, are kept by Neverware solely for internal purposes.

  *  **Opting Out:** All collected data is required by Neverware to be able to facilitate use of the portal and allow us to communicate about important product changes.

 _How long we keep the data that my.Neverware collects:_

  * When you cease to be a user of my.Neverware, you can request to have your personal info and activity erased by sending a request to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#91f5f0e5f0bcf8ffe0e4f8e3f8f4e2d1fff4e7f4e3e6f0e3f4bff2fefc).

## Cookies & Tracking Policy

When you visit our site, we may use cookies, web beacons, clear gifs, pixels and other similar technologies to automatically collect information such as your IP address, browser type and language, operating system, location, date and time.

 **Consent**

By using the Neverware website, you consent to the use of cookies in accordance with this Cookies & Tracking Policy. You will have seen a pop-up alerting you to this on your first visit to the website; although it may not appear on subsequent visits. You may withdraw your consent at any time by following the instructions below.

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your device. Web beacons are clear electronic images that can recognize certain types of information on your device, such as cookies, when you viewed a particular website tied to the web beacon, and a description of a website tied to the web beacon.

 Our site primarily uses the following four types of cookies:

 **1\. Operationally Necessary Cookies**

These cookies are essential for the operation of our website. They make it possible for you to browse and use our website. If you disable these cookies, the website will not function correctly.

 **2\. Performance Cookies**

These cookies gather information about how visitors use and interact with our services. For example, performance cookies tell us which pages are popular, monitor traffic to our website and compile anonymous analytic information. Performance cookies can also be used to identify and remedy operational problems with the website.

 **3\. Functionality Cookies**

These cookies are used to recognize and remember your preferences. For example, functionality cookies may use information, such as your location, to make sure that you arrive at a version of our site that is specific to your city or region.

 **4\. Advertising Cookies**

These cookies are used to show relevant advertising about our services on third party websites (i.e., websites that we do not own or operate). When you visit our website, we will serve a cookie on your device. This cookie will have information about how you interacted with our website, such as what pages on the site you looked at. Then, if you visit a website within an ad network that we work with, the ad network will read the cookie from your device and show you relevant advertising about our services.

Our emails contain cookies that track whether you open our emails and whether you click any links within them. The cookies used in our emails to monitor these behaviors are unique to each email. They are not stored on your computer or mobile device.

 **Avoiding and/or Disabling Cookies**

If you do not agree to the use of these cookies, you can disable them by following the instructions for your browser set out at [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). However, be aware that choosing to reject cookies may reduce the performance and functionality of our site. While Neverware’s site at this time generally does not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, such as “do not track” instructions, you can generally express your privacy preferences regarding the use of most cookies and similar technologies through your web browser.

In addition, you can opt out of third-party personalized advertising cookies on the Digital Advertising Alliance’s consumer choice page ([http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/)), the Network Advertising Initiative’s consumer choice page ([http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/)), or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance consumer choice page ([http://youronlinechoices.eu](http://youronlinechoices.eu/)).

Other tools offered by third parties can help you see and manage the types of cookies and trackers that you encounter. More information about cookies and cookie management can be found on [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/).

## Who We Share Your Data With

We may share your personal data with third parties:

  * To provide our services to you, such as to enable you to purchase services on our site, to collect payment, to set up an account for you and to ensure that such account is secure, and to enable us to identify you as a user of our services.

  * To communicate effectively with you and conduct our business—such as providing you with administrative emails and corresponding with you when you register to receive information or provide any correspondence, such as posting a comment on our blog. We will also communicate with you in relation to enquiries you make about employment opportunities.

  * For research and development purposes—for example, when you participate in a survey.

  * To provide you with marketing materials—for example, sending you promotional materials, newsletters, upgrades and special offers about our services.

  * To participate in partnerships with third party companies—for example, to provide our services by way of co-branded or private labelled websites or to enter into reseller agreements.

  * To monitor certain activities—for example, a user’s movements around the site, such as the date and time of your visit, details of the information collected through cookies and other tracking methodologies, including but not limited to your IP address, domain name, browser type, operating system and the solutions and information for which you searched. We also monitor activities as part of our compliance procedures and to combat fraud.

  * To administer our site, including to ensure that the content is relevant and presented to you in the most effective manner.

  * To comply with our legal obligations, including to comply with relevant laws and to respond to subpoenas, warrants or other requests served on Neverware anywhere in the world or to protect or defend the rights or property of Neverware or its users.

We also post customer testimonials on our site that may contain personally identifiable information. We obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.  If you would like your testimonial removed, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#7410150015591d1a05011d061d1107341a11021106031506115a171b19).

Regardless of any choices you make regarding your personal data (as described below), Neverware may disclose personal data if it believes in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on Neverware; or (b) protect or defend the rights or property of Neverware or users of the site or services.

If Neverware is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal data, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal data.

Except as otherwise stated in this policy, we do not sell, trade, share, or rent the personal data collected from our site and services to third parties other than as outlined in this policy.

## How to View, Correct, or Delete our Data About You

We offer you choices regarding the collection, use, and sharing of your personal data. If you sign up for our mailing lists or otherwise initiate an action with us while acting in an individual capacity (and not as the representative of a business or organization), we may periodically send you free newsletters and emails that directly promote the use of our site or the purchase of our products and services, subject to your consent if you are based in the EEA. When you receive newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the email you receive or by contacting us directly. Despite your indicated email preferences, we may send you notices of any updates to our Terms of Service or Privacy Policy.

 **Your other rights**

If you are based in the EEA, please see the section below to review your choices regarding your Personal Data Data Subject Rights.

Otherwise, you may change any of your Personal Data in your account by sending an email to us at the email address set forth below.  You may request deletion of your account information by us by sending an email to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#c1a5a0b5a0eca8afb0b4a8b3a8a4b281afa4b7a4b3b6a0b3a4efa2aeac), but please note that we may be required (by law or otherwise) to keep this information and not delete it (or to keep this information for a certain time, in which case we will comply with your deletion request only after we have fulfilled such requirements).  We will endeavor to respond without delay. We will otherwise retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you Services as well as is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

 **EEA Data Subject Rights**

If you are based in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), you have several data subject rights in relation to how we use your information.

In addition to the options outlined in the section directly prior, under certain conditions, you may have the right under EU data protection laws to ask us to:

  * provide you with further details on how we use and process your Personal Data

  * provide you with a copy of your Personal Data that we hold

  * update any inaccuracies in the Personal Data we hold

  * delete Personal Data we no longer have grounds to process

  * restrict how we process your Personal Data while we consider an inquiry you have raised

In addition, under certain conditions, you have the right to:

  * where processing is based on consent, withdraw the consent at any time. If you withdraw your consent, it will not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal

  * lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority

  * object to any processing of Personal Data that we process on the “legitimate interests” or “public interests” grounds, unless our reasons for the underlying processing outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms; and

  * object to direct marketing (including any profiling for such purposes) at any time

  * transfer your information to another provider, known as the right to data portability

If you would like to exercise these rights, email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4a2e2b3e2b6723243b3f2338232f390a242f3c2f383d2b382f64292527). We will endeavor to respond without delay. We may need to ask you additional clarifying questions in order to accurately respond to your request. If we are unable to deal with your request fully within one month (due to the complexity or number of requests), we may extend this period by a further two months. Should this be necessary, we will explain the reasons why.

These rights are subject to certain exemptions to safeguards to safeguard the public interest (e.g., the prevention or the detection of crime) and our interests (e.g., the maintenance of legal privilege). We will respond to most requests within one month.

If we are unable to resolve a query or a complaint, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the data protection regulator/ supervisory authority in the country in which you are based.

 **Residents of California**

Our users who are California residents may request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, certain information about the Personal Data (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of Personal Data that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d3b7b2a7b2febabda2a6baa1bab6a093bdb6a5b6a1a4b2a1b6fdb0bcbe).

 **Children’s Online Privacy**

Neverware’s products and services are not directed to children and Neverware does not knowingly collect online personal information from children under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian of a minor under the age of 13 and believe that he or she has disclosed personal information to us, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#b2d6d3c6d39fdbdcc3c7dbc0dbd7c1f2dcd7c4d7c0c5d3c0d79cd1dddf).

 **Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices, we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:

  * We will notify you via email within 20 business days

  * We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

## How to Contact Us

If you have questions about how your information is gathered, stored, shared or used, or if you wish to exercise any of your data rights, contact us at:

Neverware

112 West 27th Street, Suite 200

New York, New York 10001

United States

[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#36525742571b5f5847435f445f5345765853405344415744531855595b)

(855) 979-9199

 **Last Updated on 2019-08-15**
